DERECK SAN MIGUEL

FULL-STACK DEVELOPMENT STUDENT / E-COMMERCE SPECIALIST

PROFILE SUMMARY

Graduated from University fo Hawaii with a bachelor's degree in International Business. I also studied in Spain and New Zealand where I was able to focus on Marketing and Management while I was abroad for a year. I decided to continue my education and currently attending UC Irvine for Full Stack Development and will be graduating on July 27th, 2019. Currently an experienced full-time E-commerce specialist with a demonstrated history of working in the consumer goods industry.

CONTACT INFORMATION

- Number: 714-488-7729
- Email: derecksanmiguel0@gmail.com
- Portfolio: https://derecksm.github.io/portfolio/
- GitHub: https://github.com/derecksm
- LinkedIn: http://bit.ly/derecksm

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- HTML5
- CSS3
- Javascript
- AJAX
- JSON
- Node.js
- MySQL
- SEO Research
- Google Analytics / Data Analysis
- Email Marketing
- Photoshop

WORK EXPERIENCE

Ecommerce Specialist

Incipio - Irvine, CA (August 2016 - Present)

- Assisted in the design of product / category pages to help create a better UX
- Devised a SEO strategy to increase leads from search engine traffic to Incipio
- Implemented online marketing promotions and seasonal sales
- Presented marketing plans, strategies, and ROI of past promotions in order to create better marketing campaigns
- Tracked keyword ranking for new devices and discovered opportunities to increase SERP ranking
- Collaborated with social media influencers and media sites for link building opportunities

Account Manager

Steele Logistics - City of Industry, CA (August 2015 - July 2016)

- Handled daily operational shipping, receiving, and transportation to major retail organizations for our clients
- Managed inventory levels and the aging of product on the shelves
- Operated as the lead point of contact for our accounts
- Maintained client satisfaction by making sure their business is running efficiently and effectively

EDUCATION

University of California, Irvine

Full Stack Development Program (Currently Attending)

 Learning front end and back end web development with a focus on mobile optimization, responsive frameworks, databases, and best code practices.

University of Hawaii at Mānoa

BBA in International Business and Entrepreneurship (2011 - 2015)

 Studied the global environment of business and how businesses must constantly adapt to their environment to succeed across borders

University of Otago (Dunedin, New Zealand)

Exchange Program (Spring 2014)

 Studied Business Management and Marketing New Zealand while doing some personal exploration and development.

University of Sevilla (Sevilla, Spain)

Study Abroad Program (Spring 2013)

 Immersed myself into Spanish culture so I could practice my Spanish daily. Learned how to be more open-minded, appreciate a variety of different cultures, and how business operations change from place to place.